Welcome to the new front line
Eye in the Sky is a drama, thriller, war film directed by Gavin Hood.
A UK-based military officer in command of a top secret drone operation to capture terrorists in Kenya discovers the targets are planning a suicide bombing and the mission escalates from “capture” to “kill.” As American pilot Steve Watts is
about to engage, a nine-year old girl enters the kill zone, triggering an international dispute reaching the highest levels of US and British government over the moral, political, and personal implications of modern warfare.
Colonel Katherine Powell, played by Helen Mirren.
Steve Watts, played by Aaron Paul.
Lieutenant General Frank Benson, played by Alan Rickman.
Jama Farah, played by Barkhad Abdi.
Brian Woodale, played by Jeremy Northam.
Carrie Gershon, played by Phoebe Fox.
Eye in the Sky is a 2015 British thriller film starring Helen
Mirren, Aaron Paul, Alan Rickman, and Barkhad Abdi.
Directed by Gavin Hood and written by Guy Hibbert, the film
explores the ethical challenges of drone warfare.
Filming began in South Africa in September 2014.
The film premiered at the 2015 Toronto International
Film Festival on 11 September 2015.
Bleecker Street distributed the film in cinemas in the United States with a
limited release on 11 March 2016 and then a wide release on 1 April.
It is the last live-action film to feature Alan Rickman, who died on 14 January 2016 (his last
film overall, Alice Through the Looking Glass, features his voice acting only).
The film was dedicated to his memory.
The film explores themes of drone, terrorism,
duringcreditsstinger, us military, air force base.
The tone is emotional and intense.